MICHAEL BUBB

Phone: +1.646.783.8769

Email: michael.bubb@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mpbubb

GitHub: github.com/mbubb

gpgKey: mbubb.devio.us/gpg/pub_key.asc

PROFILE

Linux Systems Engineer with over a decade of root access on enterprise Linux environments. I have specialized in datacenter buildouts including Hadoop clusters, Netezza analytics subnets and Aerospike clusters. Often in a 'sole sysadmin' role, I have built and lead teams as organizations have gone through rapid growth. Currently am working to improve tool building skills as well as gaining experience with infrastructure management frameworks like Ansible and Kubernetes.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Senior Systems Engineer | May 2015 - present

Forensig New York, NY. (Impact Radius as of July 2016)

- SRE for 350 servers in multiple global datacenters (98% CentOS 6.x)
- Infrastructure management (DNS, System and Network Monitoring)
- Build/Deploy with Ansible-Jenkins-Github
- Ansible project lead/ Jenkins admin
- Working towards CI with Automation engineer (Kubernetes)
- Hiring remote and local engineers
- Vendor relations (datacenters, service providers)

Systems Engineer | August 2014 – May 2015

OnDeck New York, NY.

- Linux System Administration (CentOS and Ubuntu)
- Ansible configuration
- Postgresql support

Operations Engineer | June 2010 - August 2014

Collective New York, NY.

- General Linux System Administration CentOS and Ubuntu
- Datacenter management
- Hadoop buildout and support
- Netezza administration
- Automation Cobbler; Puppet; Razor; Ansible
- DNS administration
- Bash and Python scripting
- git and github code management

- monitoring with Nagios; Boundary; Circonus; Catchpoint

Systems Administrator | 2006 – 2010

Shipco Hoboken, NJ.

- Linux and UNIX System Administration
- Debian Firewall and Samba installation and configuration
- backup management on 75 servers
- Basic configuration and setup Cisco 26xx routers and HP Procurve 25xx switches
- Organized and carried out Datacenter move of all company servers
- Datacenter management
- Responsible for purchasing and billing authorization
- Help Desk Management for a 700 employee, 50 office global company

Junior System Administrator | 2005 – 2006

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ.

While enrolled at Stevens in Computer Science I worked as a UNIX System Administrator in the NetBSD Computer lab as well as on a Beowulf Cluster.

Network and Systems Administration (independent consultant) | 2000 - 2005

- Setup networks and practice management systems for lawfirms and veterinary clinics in NYC and Northern NJ.
- Handled legal discovery/ litigation management for lawfirms.
- website hosting on a RedHat server at Datapipe.

EDUCATION

Degree

- BA English, minor in Political Science from **Rutgers University, New Bruswick** (1992).

Non-matriculated

- 40 credits Computer Science, **Stevens Institute of Technology**, Hoboken, NJ (2005-2006).
- 48 credits Comparative Literature, PhD program, NYU, New York, NY (1993-1995).

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2016 | EMR license , Hoboken Volunteer Ambulance
- 2014-present | middle school volunteer teacher (Scratch, Python), Elysian Charter School
- 2013-2015 | technical volunteer, **Milemesh**.
- 2012-present | emergency shelter and communications, **Hoboken CERT**.
- 2004-2006 | webmaster; editor, **NonServiam Press**.
- 1999-2004 | webmaster; editor, The Brooklyn Rail.
- 1995-1999 | curriculum dev; teaching manager **Berlitz Korea** Seoul, Korea.
- 1989-1991 | prep cook; garde manger, Frog and the Peach.